Edgar Omar Reyes Olivas

+52 (656) 645-02-54 | edgar0.reyes0@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/edgar-o-reyes-o/

SUMMARY

Software engineer with two years of experience in both backend and frontend parts of web and mobile software development. Self-taught, proactive and committed to personal improvement. Looking forward to collaborate in new projects in order to gain more experience and learn new things, not only about software engineering but other fields as well.

SKILLS

Programming languages and technologies: Javascript, Python, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, SQL, React, React Native, Node js, Next js, Express js.

Languages: Spanish (native), Fluent English (613 score in TOEFL ITP).

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Engineer

June 2023 – Present

Foxconn PCE Technology

Ciudad Juárez, Chih, MX

- Fullstack applications development using FAST API as backend service and React JS + Next JS as frontend frameworks.
- · Software requirements gathering from internal stakeholders.
- Maintenance to applications built in Javascript with Vue.js framework.

Frontend / Mobile Developer

June 2022 – June 2023

Evolución Ventamóvil

Ciudad Juárez, Chih, MX

- Development of an eCommerce module for the sale of SIM cards and electronic devices in Axios Mobile's CRM, built with Javascript, Next is, React is, CSS and HTML.
- Built a mobile app for Android and iOS used by Evolución Ventamovil's vendors for product sales and users network management, built with Javascript and React Native.

Desarrollador Backend

Septiembre 2021 – Junio 2022

Evolución Ventamóvil

Ciudad Juarez, Chih, MX

- Built a RESTful API with Javascript, Express js, Node js and MongoDB, which serves the mobile and web apps of a Mexican cellphone carrier (Axios Mobile).
- Development of a micro service using Node js and SOAP for the automation of the porting process (cellphone carrier switch), managing up to 130 daily ports.
- RESTful APIs and SOAP based web services for the integration of external services.
- · Software requirements gathering with internal company members.
- · Collaboration with team members in order to design new features for the project.

Fullstack Developer

January 2021 – April 2021

Consejo Estatal de Población del Estado de Chihuahua

Ciudad Juarez, Chih, MX

- Development of a fullstack app using Javascript, Node js, Express js and MongoDB as backend and React js as frontend, this system was used to capture migrant people data and to generate statistical graphics with this data.
- · Deployment of a web app using a Linux server hosted in a Digital Ocean droplet.

EDUCATION

Universidad Autónoma de Ciudad Juárez

Ciudad, Juarez, Chih, MX

B.S Software Engineering

August 2017 – November 2022

ACADEMIC & RESEARCH PROJECTS

University of Alberta

Edmonton, Alberta, Canada

Learning Analytics Dashboard

May 2022 – August 2022

National Institute of Electricity and Clean Energies

Cuernavaca, Mor, MX

Junio 2021 – Julio 2021

Photovoltaic Energy Forecasting Model Using Artificial Intelligence